Welcome to our training on Amazon anti-counterfeiting policy compliance.
The tips we'll share in this video don't take the place of legal advice.
So, remember to consult a lawyer.
If you have any specific anti-counterfeiting or intellectual property questions, when you list products
in the Amazon store, you'll need to comply with all applicable laws and Amazon policies.
One of these policies is the Amazon anti-counterfeiting policy.
Which helps ensure that all products in the Amazon store are authentic.
When you sell in the Amazon store, you agree that all of your products are authentic.
Some examples of inauthentic or counterfeit products include bootlegs, fakes, pirated copies of
products or content.
Products that have been illegally replicated, reproduced, or manufactured, and products that infringe
on another party's intellectual property rights.
To help avoid selling counterfeit and inauthentic products, we recommend sourcing your products
from a reliable supplier and verifying that they're authentic.
Before you list them, in certain cases, an Amazon selling partner will list an authentic product,
but customers or other sellers might think it's inauthentic.
To help avoid this misunderstanding, we recommend listing and shipping products in the, manufacturer's
original packaging, and refraining from altering or removing the brand's packaging, which contains
important product information.
Let's review an example of a product listing.
That doesn't comply with our anti-counterfeiting policy.
A seller lists a handbag in the Amazon store.
On its product detail page, the seller notes that the handbag is from brand ABC.
A customer sees the product listing, notices the brand name product's low price, and makes a purchase.
When the handbag arrives, the customer discovers that the handbag isn't one of the brand's authentic
products and contacts Amazon.
In this example, the seller has violated the Amazon anti-counterfeiting policy.
Sellers who don't comply with this or other selling policies may experience the following.
The listings that are in violation may be suspended.
Their funds may be withheld in accordance with applicable laws or Amazon's funds withholding policy.
Their FBA product inventory may be removed or disposed of in accordance with applicable laws or
Amazon's business solutions agreement.
And their selling account may be either suspended or deactivated.
When you and other sellers comply with the anti-counterfeiting policy, you help ensure customers
can trust the products they buy in the Amazon store.
To review the Amazon anti-counterfeiting policy, search for anti-counterfeiting policy in Seller
Central.
This concludes our training on how to comply with the Amazon anti-counterfeiting policy.
Thank you and happy selling in the Amazon store.